aps.edu 2018-12-05

# Privacy Statement & Legal Disclaimers — Albuquerque Public Schools

We at APS are committed to protecting the privacy and security of your visits to this website. Outlined below is our web content accessibility statement, online privacy statement, acceptable use policy, and legal disclaimers. If you have questions about this information, [please let us know](http://www.aps.edu/contact-us "Contact Us").

## Web Content Accessibility

The website is the work of many authors and is a dynamic environment. There is the possibility that accessibility difficulties may be encountered.

If there is information that you require and it is in a format that you cannot access, please contact the specific department who authored or provided the information.

If you are experiencing any other accessibility issues, please [contact the Web Team](http://www.aps.edu/web-team/accessibility/website-accessibility-feedback-form).

## Privacy Statement

Collection and disclosure of information: To ensure we are able to communicate effectively with visitors to our web site, we collect some information that can be directly associated with a specific person. We call this "Personal Information," and it includes, by way of illustration, names, addresses, telephone numbers and e-mail addresses.

We collect Personal Information from eligible individuals who affirmatively request to receive e-mail or other services from us. We collect this Personal Information in order to provide these eligible individuals with timely information via e-mail regarding events, resources, and issues.

It is our general policy not to make Personal Information available to anyone other than our employees, staff, and agents.

Please be aware that Personal Information may be discoverable in court and administrative proceedings and in accordance with public records laws.

Opting out and modifying information: Subscribers to our e-mail list may terminate their subscriptions via a link at the bottom of each email sent from aps.edu.

Browser information collected on the web site: We log IP addresses, which are the locations of computers or networks on the Internet, and analyze them in order to improve the value of our site. We also collect aggregate numbers of page hits to track the popularity of certain pages and improve the value of our site. We do not gather, request, record, require, collect or track any Internet users' Personal Information through these processes.

Cookies: A cookie is a tiny piece of data stored by a user's browser that helps a web site or service recognize that user's unique computer. You can remove or block cookies by changing the settings of your browser.

Session specific cookies may be used on aps.edu to improve the user experience and for basic web metrics. These cookies expire in a very short time frame or when a browser window closes.

Privacy of our email lists: As noted above, we maintain e-mail lists to keep interested, eligible individuals informed about important topics, and individuals must affirmatively request to join them. We configure our list server software to refuse to divulge the email addresses of our list subscribers to anyone other than those whom we authorize. However, we are not the author of this software and are not responsible for any failures in the software to preserve subscriber anonymity.

Children's privacy: Because we care about the safety and privacy of children online, we comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). COPPA and its accompanying FTC regulation establish United States federal law that protects the privacy of children using the Internet. We do not knowingly contact or collect personal information from children under 13. Our site is not intended to solicit information of any kind from children under 13.

It is possible that by fraud or deception we may receive information pertaining to children under 13. If we are notified of this, as soon as we verify the information, we will immediately obtain parental consent to retain the information or else delete the information from our servers. If you want to notify us of our receipt of information pertaining to children under 13, [please contact us](http://www.aps.edu/contact-us "Contact Us").

## Disclaimer: Limitation of Liability

The Albuquerque Public School District makes no warranties of any kind, either express or implied, that the functions or the services provided by or through the Albuquerque Public School District system will be error-free or without defect. The Albuquerque Public School District will not be responsible for any damage users may suffer, including but not limited to, loss of data or interruptions of service. The Albuquerque Public School District is not responsible for the accuracy or quality of the information obtained through or stored on the system. The Albuquerque Public School District will not be responsible for financial obligations arising from a user’s unauthorized use of the system.

By using this site, you agree to indemnify and hold the Albuquerque Public School District including, but not limited to, its officers, board members, employees, and agents harmless from any losses sustained by the Albuquerque Public School District as a result of intentional or negligent misuse of the system by a user.

Please be advised that the information contained here is accurate as of January 2010. Since [policies and procedural directives](http://www.aps.edu/about-us/policies-and-procedural-directives) of the Albuquerque Public School District change from time to time, it is suggested that the accuracy of the information contained herein be verified.

The Albuquerque Public School District reserves the right to change this policy without notice.

## Internet Acceptable Use Policy

Students: The Albuquerque Public School District provides technology resources to its students for educational purposes. The goal of providing these resources is to promote educational excellence.

Proper behavior, as it relates to the use of computers, is no different from the proper behavior in all other aspects of APS activities. All users are expected to use the computers and computer networks in a responsible, ethical, and polite manner. Violation of this policy is grounds for school disciplinary action.

Students are expected to comply with the Student Internet Acceptable Use Policy, as set out above and in the [J18 Acceptable Student Use of Educational Technology](http://www.aps.edu/about-us/policies-and-procedural-directives/policies/j.-students/ji8-acceptable-student-use-of-educational-technology).[  
](http://www.aps.edu/about-us/policies-and-procedural-directives/policies/j.-students/ji8-acceptable-student-use-of-educational-technology)

Employees: The use of district technology resources is a privilege granted to Albuquerque Public School District employees for the enhancement of job-related functions. Employees may have limited access to these resources for personal use, if they comply with the professional standards and the district’s acceptable use policies. Employees are expected to comply with the [Technology Acceptable Use Policy](http://www.aps.edu/about-us/policies-and-procedural-directives/policies/g.-personnel/gb6-acceptable-employee-use-of-technology), as set out in APS Procedural Directives.

Updated: January 7, 2010

Updated: May 7, 2018
